<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modern IT Engineer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Modern IT Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:25:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Agentic AI Simulation Land</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/agentic-ai-infra-sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 01:25:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/agentic-ai-infra-sim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Or, How We Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Cloud)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how a cloud-based, multi-agent AI service handles a flurry of incoming user requests without spontaneously combusting? Well, wonder no more! In this blog post, we’ll embark on a fun, light-hearted journey through a simulation that tests just how gracefully an AI agentic system (think: a set of AI agents working together) scales, splits, and handles all sorts of query traffic. We’ll talk about our framework, assumptions, code, and results—complete with a snazzy chart to show off our data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Traffic Flow through Azure Firewall Using PowerShell, Jupyter, and d3js</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/sankey-d3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 21:36:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/sankey-d3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script type=&#34;module&#34; src=&#34;display.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello again. This time, let&amp;rsquo;s look at how to visualize traffic flowing through Azure Firewall using PowerShell, Jupyter, and D3.js.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Azure Networking using D3js</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/azure-networking-d3js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 16:26:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/azure-networking-d3js/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script type=&#34;module&#34; src=&#34;display.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
#side-card {
    width: 20%;
    overflow-y: auto;
    background: #fff; /* Background color */
    padding: 10px;
    box-shadow: 0 4px 8px rgba(0,0,0,0.1); /* Shadow for raised effect */
    border-radius: 5px; /* Optional: adds rounded corners */
}

#node-list {
    display: grid;
    grid-template-columns: repeat(2, 1fr); /* Creates two columns */
    gap: 5px; /* Space between items */
    list-style: none; /* Removes default list styling */
    padding: 0;
}

#node-list li {
    background: #f8f8f8; /* Light background for each item */
    padding: 5px;
    border-radius: 3px; /* Rounded corners for list items */
    cursor: pointer; /* Indicates interactivity */
}

#filter-input {
    margin-bottom: 10px; /* Spacing between input and list */
    padding: 8px;
    width: calc(100% - 16px); /* Full width taking padding into account */
    box-sizing: border-box; /* Includes padding and border in width */
    border-radius: 5px; /* Rounded corners for input */
    border: 1px solid #ccc; /* Subtle border for the input */
}

#node-list li:hover {
    background-color: lightgray;  // Highlight list item on hover
    cursor: pointer;
}

circle {
    transition: all 0.3s ease;  // Smooth transition for changes in size and color
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A picture worth a thousand words. When you work with a complex networking infrastructure, it would be great to have a bird&amp;rsquo;s-eye view of it. In this article, I want to discuss how this can be achieved using PowerShell, Jupyter notebooks, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://d3js.org/&#34;&gt;d3js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make ZScaler and Azure CLI Work Together</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/how-to-deal-with-zscaler-and-azcli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 19:39:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/how-to-deal-with-zscaler-and-azcli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are times when ZScaler can get quite bothersome, and recently, I had one of those moments. This note aims to share the steps needed to get the Azure CLI to cooperate with ZScaler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuing the Conversation on Jupyter and PowerShell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/more-notebooks-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 22:06:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/more-notebooks-ps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive a little deeper into the Jupyter-PowerShell duo. First, we’ll try to uncover the ‘why’ behind this alliance. Next, we’ll pry into the ‘how’ of the operation. And finally, we&amp;rsquo;ll unveil the secrets of crafting a notebook and launching it into the digital cosmos for your team or, who knows, the whole world to see. Ready? Set. Go!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do we always need to follow CAF recommendations?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/no-caf-webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 09:46:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/no-caf-webapps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the journey of infrastructure creation within Azure, many organizations lean towards crafting complex hub-and-spoke topologies to host their applications, even when the necessity for such complexity isn’t apparent. A common justification echoes: “It’s mandated by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cloud-adoption-framework/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework (CAF)&lt;/a&gt;”. However, embarking on this path unfolds a myriad of related, albeit previously unexplored, domains. For instance, the newfound need to manage IP spaces, delve into VLSM subnetting - topics unfamiliar to most Dev teams. Once networked, the quest doesn’t end; it merely morphs into challenges like private DNS resolution, establishing access to internal resources, and the list trails on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, if we pause to reflect, many Azure services including Azure Web Apps were designed with a public persona. Initially, some didn’t even entertain VNET integration, and this model was well-accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we aim to traverse a less convoluted route towards securely hosting Web Apps, whilst sidestepping the network-centric hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approach to Optimizing VM Costs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/aproach-to-optimizing-vm-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 12:48:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/aproach-to-optimizing-vm-costs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you considering transitioning your servers from an on-prem DC to Azure cloud? One step in this journey involves mapping existing servers to their Azure counterparts. The goal is to reduce the costs of the overall bundle of boxes while obtaining the highest possible performance. In theory, we can map the source VMs to the target VMs based on the number of virtual CPUs and the amount of RAM. Although this isn&amp;rsquo;t the most challenging task, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t guarantee the highest possible performance for the lowest possible price. If we always opt for a VM with the lowest price, we may compromise on performance. Conversely, choosing VMs with the highest performance could result in higher costs. Is there a middle ground? Is it possible to achieve what we want? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to automate IP ranges calculations in Azure using PowerShell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/using-ipmgmt-more-samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 18:39:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/using-ipmgmt-more-samples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose we have been allocated the IP range of &lt;code&gt;10.172.0.0/16&lt;/code&gt; by the network team for planned Azure Landing Zones. The goal is to automate this by creating a tool that will automatically calculate IP ranges for us, based on some high-level and easy-to-understand details regarding the future networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This notebook demonstrates how to achieve this using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eosfor/ipmgmt&#34;&gt;ipmgmt&lt;/a&gt; module.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using IP management module</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/ipmgmt-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 01:38:48 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/ipmgmt-module/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Assume we&amp;rsquo;ve got three different ranges &amp;lsquo;10.192.0.0/11&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;10.64.0.0/11&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;10.128.0.0/11&amp;rsquo;. These ranges correspond to three different geographic locations in Azure. There are already some ranges used in these top level blocks. And we have the whole list of ranges, which are in use already. So what we want to achieve is we want to automatically select the next available range and provision VNET for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations when running private AKS cluster</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/aks-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 05:03:31 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/aks-considerations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last two weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/aks/&#34;&gt;Azure Kubernetes Service&lt;/a&gt; (AKS) and with it&amp;rsquo;s public counterpart - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/acs-engine&#34;&gt;acs-engine&lt;/a&gt;. Here is a bit about the experience I got with it, having in mind I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked with these tools before. Here I&amp;rsquo;m trying to look at this from the Infrastructure perspective, but not from the developers&amp;rsquo; perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Powershell to analyze Sysmon events</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/powershell-graph-sysmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 13:37:07 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/powershell-graph-sysmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello colleagues, this is an example I promised answering &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cyb3rops/status/895024725730238464&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; tweet. I used this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SwiftOnSecurity/sysmon-config&#34;&gt;sysmon config&lt;/a&gt; to capture activities happening on my system. Unfortunately it did not capture a lot of network-related activities, perhaps I need to change it to extend network-level filters. But on the other hand it captured a lot of process level activities, so in this example i&amp;rsquo;d like to try to graph process creation events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using graphs to analyze Windows Firewall logs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/graphs-windows-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:53:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/graphs-windows-firewall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello colleagues, lets talk about how we can use graphs to look inside of communications happening in our environments in an easy way. First of all we need to have some data to analyze. Lets gather some. It is pretty simple - just use &lt;a href=&#34;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc947815%28v=ws.10%29.aspx&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; and enable Windows Firewall Logging. I usually put the logs into a separate folder, just for easy access. Here is how it looks like on my system:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing VM Search in Azure with PowerShell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/search-azure-objects2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 10:35:09 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/search-azure-objects2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this walkthrough, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore various functionalities of PowerShell, including dynamic parameters, parallel execution of script blocks, and index building for efficient searches, among other features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in by understanding the problem at hand. Often, there&amp;rsquo;s a need to search VMs not only by their names but also by their internal IP addresses or the names of their disks. However, the absence of an out-of-the-box API for this task led me to develop a custom tool. The goals were outlined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Azure Objects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/article/search-azure-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 19:35:54 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/article/search-azure-objects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our environment we have more than one subscription. Even more than five. And this amount grows constantly. What we do with all of this is we support VMs and stuff there. One of the issues is that users usually do not know name of Azure Service which is used to host their VMs, and it so happens that they do not know even their Subscription Name or Subscription ID. To bring up and control their VMs and environments the use some “middleware” which hides all of this info from them. So they usually come to us and say: “here you are a list of VMs we have problems with, please have a look and fix”. Sometimes such list contains not only VMs but storage accounts along with VMs etc. Unfortunately classic azure cmdlets does not provide an option to search for objects in the cloud by their name. On the other hand new Azure Management portal does. It can find objects by name. So I decided to do a little hack end use this API in order to simplify our live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
